- ( crashing )
- ( alarm blaring )
( metal creaking )
( alarm continues )
( crashing )
( gasping )
- ( crashing )
- ( metal creaking )
Automated voice:
Rejuvenation commenced.
Compression suits activated.
There's been a breach. We
gotta get everyone out of the bay.
- What happened?
- Hell if I know.
( beeps )
Go. go. go. go. Go. go. go. go.
( overlapping shouts )
Oh. Susan! Susan. no!
( beeps )
The room is collapsing! Go. go!
Everybody. get in! Get in there!
Secure your helmets
until we stabilize!
- Come on. move! Move!
- Get in there!
Get your helmets!
Secure your helmets
until we stabilize!
( panting. muttering )
Trent! Trent. come on.
we have to go!
The bay's imploding.
We have to go.
- No! Please. I gotta try!
- Trent.
- Come on.
- No!
No.
( all shouting )
( beeps )
Oh. no.
( all shouting )
( grunting )
( screaming )
( theme music playing )
Where the hell are we going?
We need to speak
to our commanding officers.
- find out what just happened.
- Whoa. whoa. wait.
We're going to the commanding
officers' cryo bay?
I'm not waking up
Captain Lester.
I think this more than qualifies
as sufficient emergency.
Seriously?
Fine. I'll wake her up.
( chattering. coughing )
When in God's name will someone
tell us what happened?
I heard a fuel tank exploded.
Yeah. I heard
we hit an asteroid.
But I'd like someone
from command to brief us.
Please do not spread
unsubstantiated rumors.
I'm sure we will know
when they know.
Until then. we follow protocol.
Excuse me. Is this Med Bay 12?
- I was messaged to report to...
- Group 3. you're late.
Get on the table over there
and get out of
your compression suit.
( grunts )
Kabir: I said table first.
then suit.
- My legs!
- You've been in a cryogenic state
for a long time.
A certain amount
of muscle atrophy occurs
even while wearing the suit.
Will I ever get my legs back?
My God. man. did you pay
no attention during orientation?
There was a lot to take in.
You'll be out of your suit
and on your feet soon
if you make all
your rehab appointments.
- Okay.
- On time.
James Brice? Is there a
Lieutenant James Brice in here?
Aye.
You're wanted on Cent-Com. stat.
Well. I'm assigned
to navigation.
I haven't worked Cent-Com
since I was a wee lad.
- Today you work Cent-Com.
- Aye. aye. Captain.
Lieutenant. just like you.
( laughs ) Lieutenant?
So how can I help you.
Lieutenant?
We can't access the flight log
and cam recordings.
We need to know what happened.
what our status is.
- but we're locked out.
- Look. I'll be honest.
I don't even know if I remember
how it works. Cent-Com.
I mean. shouldn't
Mayweather be doing this?
He practically lives
for this shit.
Mayweather is dead.
along with everyone else
in the commanding
officers' cryo bay.
That must be the last load.
I have no charges left.
Any word from command
about what happened?
No one knows nothing.
I'm going to need more
refill tanks for the helmets.
- Good for you.
- You're life support system! You get them for me.
Fetching canisters
is below my paygrade. comrade.
I'm Serbian. you moron.
You certainly are.
I was so worried I lost you.
You wanna put us in trouble?
I didn't know
what was happening.
where you were.
or even if you were alive.
If someone was to see us.
start poking around...
I mean. does that even matter
anymore? We're on the ship now.
What are they gonna do?
Throw us off?
Don't be so sure they would not.
I broke many laws
putting you on my team.
but no one
can find out about us.
Is that clear?
Automated voice: All personnel
required in the mess hall on C Deck.
All personnel. No exceptions.
All personnel required
in the mess hall of C Deck.
All personnel. No exceptions.
Sorry. sorry.
( indistinct chatter )
Hey. mind if I sit here?
Sure. I'm Alicia Nevins.
Some people call me Ali.
Not that that's a preference.
It just kinda happens.
Oh. I'm on the waste
management team. I... I know. Gross.
But it's not like I didn't apply
to every other branch
on the ship first.
But. hey. it got me on the ship.
And my family are actually
really supportive.
But why wouldn't they be. right?
If we actually succeed
in building
a sustainable colony.
all of our families
get to be the first to
come out and settle there.
Um. who are you?
Call me Angus. In horticulture.
Wait. I know you.
You're that farmer boy.
You grew crops
in the Mojave Desert.
Well. I can see
why they'd want you.
Growing food on alien planet
we've never seen before
- is gonna be insane.
- Yeah.
It scares the bejesus out of me.
But getting to learn
from Major Andrews?
That's a dream of mine.
He's a legendary horticulturist.
- Okay. listen up.
- I'm not gonna beat around the bush.
We've all been
in cryogenic sleep
for exactly
five years and 92 days.
which means
once we get back to speed.
we still have over a year to go
before reaching Proxima B.
No one told us
what happened to the ship.
- We don't know.
- What do you mean you don't know?
It could've been an asteroid.
space junk.
Hell. a fuel cell
could've burst.
There's been a series of
malfunctions while we were asleep.
The ship's monitoring
cameras went down.
so there's no recording
of what happened.
But whatever happened.
it knocked it off course.
The good news is navigation systems
are back up and I've course corrected.
Both sleeper pod bays
were destroyed.
the rear storage units. as well as
two ballasts. and the reclamation unit.
which means we can't recycle
any of our water.
We carry roughly
a four-week supply onboard.
Garnet: We believe the water
recycling unit we have for the colony
can be retrofitted to work here
on the ship.
We just have to repurpose it.
Until then.
we are on tight rations.
This means no showers. laundry.
or any unnecessary water uses.
What if we're not able
to repurpose it?
Even with rationing.
how long do we have
before the water runs out?
- Let's think positively.
- ( scoffs )
- We'll make a functioning unit.
- Yeah.
In the manifest. it said
that we weren't to wake up
until two weeks before landing.
So aside from the water.
what about food?
Do we have enough supplies to
survive a year out of the sleeper pods?
We had been carrying
a year's supply.
but that was held
in the storage units we lost.
( sighs )
Garnet: This ship has an
additional six weeks of food.
but we will need to reserve
some of that for post arrival.
You expect to ration six weeks
of food for over a year?
Okay. I demand to hear
from Captain Lester.
- Where's the Captain?
- She's dead.
( gasping. murmuring )
What about Stuber?
No? Monroe? Rodriguez?
We lost them all
in the incident.
( chatter )
( sighs )
The entire high command.
the mentor class.
our top engineers. scientists.
architects. teachers.
everybody that was in charge
of running this ship
in Pod Bay 1 are dead.
It all falls to us now.
The three of us
standing before you
are the highest ranking officers
left on this ship.
- Then who's in charge?
- I am.
- Excuse me?
- We all have the same rank.
Each of you specialize
in different aspects
of this ship.
I have the most working
knowledge of all of the ship.
When we get past this. you can elect
whomever you like to be in command.
I have no ambition
for governing.
I care about survival.
and frankly.
I'm our best shot at it.
Our food supply was intended
for 400 people.
There are only 150 of us left.
Therefore.
our limited food supply
should last us
three times longer.
More than that with rationing.
This ship
had amazing leadership.
and they were brought together
to nurture us
into becoming
the colony's future.
But they're all gone now.
We don't have
the luxury of time.
Each and every one of you
was chosen
because you're the smartest
people in your fields.
We have some of the most gifted
and skilled craftsmen.
brilliant engineers
and scientists.
chosen to build a colony
from scratch on an alien planet.
to save mankind.
To save our families back home.
Starting today.
we have to expect more
from each other...
...and of ourselves.
We have no alternatives.
We grieve the brave men
and women
who devoted themselves
and paid the ultimate sacrifice
for the viability.
the very existence
of this mission.
As we remember these kind souls.
let us not lose ourselves
in grief.
Instead. let us celebrate
the lives that these...
Saw you try to save Commander
Ingram when everything went to hell.
Aw. she was a right pill.
that one.
- You guys we close. huh?
- Susan handpicked me for this.
She changed my life.
She saved my life.
I get why the three
lowest ranking lieutenants
were put in the pod bays
with the rest of us peasants.
but why would they put
Ingram in with us?
Strange. right?
...those born with an exceptional
drive to make this universe
a better place
for the rest of us.
And like the rest of us.
they left the comfort...
That was very impressive
last night.
A little presumptive.
but very take charge.
Perhaps you didn't need to be
quite so honest though. you know?
It might've inspired a little more
confidence if they actually felt
we knew how to safely
get to our destination.
They're not children.
They volunteered to be here.
They deserve an honest command.
Right. and naturally
you're the best person
to step up to the plate.
I'm the person who did step up.
What the hell did you do?
Speaker:
These people were our friends.
friends we laughed with.
cried with.
friends whose courageous spirits
led them all on a journey
of science and discovery.
They were the brightest stars
in their fields.
- Hey. can I talk with you?
- I'm very busy right now.
Oh. please. I just need a
couple minutes of your time.
- Captain Garnet...
- Lieutenant.
Yes. Sorry. I get
confused with all the titles
and ranks and stuff. I know there's
some kind of chain of command. but...
You're that 4H kid. right?
I guess. Sure.
There's something
you wanna say to me?
No. I have something
I wanna show you.
Is this breakfast
or a wedding ring?
( gasps )
- Are you proposing?
- You're hilarious.
What's that supposed to be?
500 calories
and your water rations.
We're gonna try to live
on 500 calories a day?
You get one in the morning.
another at night.
Oh. well. in that case...
You wouldn't happen to have.
like. a vegan alternative.
- Maybe something gluten-free?
- Next.
I mean. 1.000 calories a day
is not a lot to live on.
depending on height. age.
weight. and body type.
Most major studies say that a
minimum of 1.200 calories is required.
In fact. the Center
for Human Nutrition
still maintains eating
fewer than 1.000 calories
has the same physiological
effects as total starvation.
So we're right on the edge
of famishment.
But I guess a few of us onboard
could stand to lose
a few pounds.
Oh. Uh...
That was really inappropriate.
I'm sorry.
I'm nervous.
and when I'm nervous.
I tend to run off at the mouth. and I
don't know what I'm saying sometimes.
Wait. you didn't finish
your ration.
Oh. you can have it.
I've lost my appetite.
- You sure you don't mind?
- Mm-hmm.
Major Andrews put me in charge
of loading the gear
and supplies.
so I control the inventory.
If you're trying to tell me
some of your gear is missing. I...
No. No. no. not missing.
In fact.
I'm showing you something
I wasn't supposed to bring.
Uh...
- What the hell is that?
- Soil.
The most fertile on Earth.
Chemically modified
by yours truly
to make it into a super soil.
Okay. I thought the planet we
were headed to had appropriate soil.
Oh. that's what was reported
by the probe we sent.
but I didn't wanna get there
and find out it was wrong
and we all starved to death.
Okay. so you suddenly felt
the need to confess
- you brought unauthorized cargo.
- No.
Yeah. right now we have bigger
issues than misdemeanor illegal...
I can grow crops
in this stuff anywhere.
- Anywhere.
- Don't you need sunlight?
Yeah. yeah.
I brought agricultural LEDs.
Lots of them.
They need a lot of power.
Power we got.
Where do you wanna setup?
How much of the stuff in here
can we move someplace else?
- Don't touch that.
- ( gasps )
Oh. my God. You frightened me.
I'm going to have to
ask you to leave.
You shouldn't sneak up
on a lady like that.
You can't be in here.
Until we can recycle
our water again.
these showers are off-limits.
Couldn't you make just
a small exception?
- Don't.
- I just really need a quick rinse.
- Madam. please.
- You can watch. You'll see.
I won't run the water
hardly at all. honest.
See? I just need
a short rinse off.
- No one has to know.
- It'll be our little secret.
Please.
I'm sorry.
( sighs )
I thought the sewage system
used air pressure.
And a small amount of water.
which we now need elsewhere.
Help me.
Stack these over there.
Whoa. Hold up.
You can't bring
all of that down in here.
There's not enough room
for this.
People need to work down here.
We're moving these crates to all
available spaces around the ship.
- You're not the only one complaining.
- What's going on?
Had to empty out Storage Hold 3.
- Make way.
- Coming through.
Please tell me this is exactly
what I think it is.
Depends on what you think it is.
You're building a bio
shelter farm on the ship.
That's amazing. You're amazing.
Major Andrews would be
so proud of you.
Well. we're just
trying this out.
It's gonna be a week or more
before we have an idea
if this has a chance of working.
- A lot could go wrong.
- What can I do to help?
Oh. nothing. We just have...
Didn't you tell me
you work in waste management?
Yes. Why?
I'm gonna need
a ton of fertilizer.
- Ew.
- Yeah.
Eww.
- Hey. sport.
- Hi.
- Hey. doody head.
- Stop it.
- We know you're still sleeping.
- For. like. a year.
Mother: And you probably won't
see this until just before you land.
But we want you to know that
we think about you all the time.
Father:
We're so proud of you. Baylor.
Mother: We love you. and we know
that we'll all be reunited
in the colony that you build.
Your family?
I was checking the last burst
of communications to the ship.
- One of them just happened to be...
- It's fine. Trent. honestly.
That message
was nearly four years ago.
We haven't received
any communications at all.
I know. I reviewed the logs.
How was that even possible?
Nothing from command?
You think everything's okay
back home?
We have no way of knowing.
If even just one of those
relay satellites broke down.
- we'd lose communications.
- ( sighs )
My family wanted me accepted
onto this program more than anything.
I failed recruitment.
Yeah. twice.
But Susan...
I mean. Commander Ingram.
yeah. she picked me anyway.
Well. she must've seen
something very special in you.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
- Shoot.
- Do you ever regret it?
You know.
volunteering for all this?
if you lose your family.
lose you your friends.
people you love...
We get our colony up
and working.
you'll see them all again.
By now the Ark program
has ships searching
the known universe
for a new home...
But not everyone
is going to make it. Trent.
It's survival of the fittest.
No one is going to
just hand this to us.
We have to take it. You get me?
( powering down )
- What was that?
- Hey. what just happened?
- We've started the rerouting.
- Rerouting? What rerouting?
Power to the storage bay.
They need a lot of it.
- Under whose orders?
- Lieutenant Garnet. sir.
- Are we good to go?
- We've quadrupled capacity for the breakers.
The storage bay wasn't meant
for this kind of juice.
- I can't promise anything.
- Okay. Light it up!
Oh. it's beautiful!
What the hell
is going on in here?
Our young 4-H wunderkind
came up with a way to build a farm.
So stringbean has an idea and
you just go steal power from the ship?
Well. it's the only way to get the
light intensity for accelerated growth.
Ah. he speaks. Perfect.
- Is there a problem here?
- Yes.
You taking unilateral action
without consulting anyone.
We have a food shortage.
This is an attempt to address it.
Why would anyone in their
right mind object to that?
Are you 100% sure
this will work?
What about you?
No doubts this will provide
edible food for the entire crew?
We're just trying
to grow produce.
And that takes water.
doesn't it?
We're planting crops that
are extremely stingy with water.
Amaranth grain. corn...
Yes. but they still need
some water. don't they?
- Yes. sir.
- It's not your water. Sharon.
It belongs to everyone
on this ship.
Now maybe this is a great idea.
maybe it isn't.
but if you're going to use
valuable resources that affect us all.
then we should have a say in it.
Nobody put you in charge.
We're just tolerating it.
You're right. I apologize.
I should've brought
everyone together
and allowed people to weigh in.
You think?
And you should've pulled me
aside and spoken with me.
Instead. you need to
grandstand and challenge me
- in front of everyone.
- Don't make this about me.
You've done that
all by yourself.
Hold off on irrigation.
I'm Dr. Sanjivni Kabir.
I'm representing
the medical staff onboard.
Felix Strickland. acting head
of security enforcement.
Eva Markovic.
acting head of maintenance.
- engineering. and construction.
- This body will serve
as the representative
voice of the ship
until the current crisis
is over.
Can someone please tell me
what's the point
of this meeting?
We've got a bleeding
food crisis. right?
The kid says he can grow crops.
so let him.
While limited. some of the water
will be needed to grow the crops.
and we're not 100% sure
this will work.
- The water could be wasted.
- Right. maybe.
But unless we can figure out how to
get more food. then we die. End of story.
There are other
considerations as well.
We're diverting power
to the labs.
which means the rest of
the ship is being deprived.
Power usage now is
approximately what it was
while we were all in the
sleeper pods. It shouldn't...
When we were
in the sleeper pods.
the life support systems
were not in use.
- There could be an adverse effect.
- Oh. could. Maybe.
We will absolutely all die
if we don't have more food.
I'm just saying we need to run
probability scenarios. do thorough testing.
Make sure we're not wasting
what little water we have left.
Instead we'd only be
wasting valuable time?
Where are we on constructing
a new water recycling unit?
We're having difficulties
finding all the necessary parts.
I'm confident we'll be able
to make a functioning unit...
Forgive me if I would like
to have something
- a little more concrete than your optimism.
- It's not easy.
We're searching in the dark
with only flashlights.
We'll get those lights back on
back in those units.
And what if the power drain
affects life support?
I mean. that could kill us
long before we starve.
Whatever we do going forward
will entail risks.
We're on a damaged ship
and we're deficient on supplies.
We're just gonna have
to make tough choices.
( clears throat )
We set the drip for three
minute intervals every 14 hours.
If there's no signs of germination within
the first four days. we'll terminate.
- Is that really enough time?
- In this soil. we should see something.
- I don't wanna waste any more water.
- We need food to survive.
Make it work.
Let's do it!
Do you really think they can
make enough food for all of us?
Maybe. but we first have to
rebuild the water recycling unit.
Okay. you got your lights.
now find those parts.
Ensign Trent. you are not scheduled
for physical therapy until tomorrow.
I know. I know. I know. I just...
I gotta get out of this suit.
It's driving me crazy.
Everyone recovers
at their own pace.
You can't speed up the process.
- ( shudders )
- You okay?
Doctor. I'm...
I'm having trouble breathing.
You have no history of asthma
or any lung problems.
Automated voice: Life support
warning. Oxygen depletion alert.
All crew members. please retrieve
compression suits and helmets.
Repeat. life support warning.
Oxygen depletion alert.
All crew members. please retrieve
compression suits and helmets.
( overlapping shouts ) -
Repeat. oxygen depletion alert.
All crew members. please retrieve
compression suits and helmets.
This inhaler will give you
some relief.
Get your suit on
and I'll grab us some helmets.
No. wait! Over here! Quickly!
Oxygen emergency.
Lockdown protocol is enacted.
( beeps )
- ( beeps )
- ( muttering )
- I'll get help.
- What the...
What the hell
is happening. Brice?
Once the ship hits
15% oxygen levels.
it automatically
goes into lockdown.
Oxygen?
Why are we losing oxygen?
I don't know.
It could be a leak.
Maybe a mechanical malfunction.
What do you mean you don't know?
I am goddamn
navigation wonk. right?
This is not my area.
So. all I can tell you
is the system diagnostics
are stuck in some kind of loop.
It won't tell me what's wrong.
how to fix it.
and I can't break it!
How long do we have
to figure this out?
Well. the suits should be good
for at least an hour of oxygen.
For anyone who wasn't able
to get a suit on?
In lockdown. all we have left is
the oxygen we have in each section.
But right now we're averaging
13%. and it's still dropping.
- ( beeps )
- ( alarm blaring )
( panting )
I don't know what coding
they've used.
- I can't crack this open.
- Where's chief life support?
That's a great goddamn question.
We put out the summons. All personnel
should be manning their stations!
Look him up. find him.
get his ass in here now!
We need a team on every deck.
See if we can find the source
of the malfunction.
- Lieutenant.
- If software can't diagnose the cause.
maybe we can through
process of elimination.
You. come with me.
We're gonna start at the front.
work our way back.
and find the problem.
Chief Jasper Dades.
what is your location?
Jasper Dades. identify yourself.
You're wanted in Cent-Com. stat.
( beeps )
- What is taking so long?
- Sasha doesn't want to damage the lock.
Tell him to get
the door open now.
Eva. what aren't you telling me?
I didn't get to that section
of the hallway yet.
Helmets in there
are practically empty.
( beeps )
- ( beeps )
- Empty.
( screams )
There are full helmets on this
side. Just get the door open!
Oxygen relay station Deck B
forward bow has no anomalies.
Did you find anything elsewhere?
Brice: Look. so far we haven't
been able to identify the anomaly.
Jasper Dades?
( no audible dialogue )
( grunts )
Move. Get out of my way.
It's unbreakable.
Save your breath.
Sasha. can we get out of here
through some air vents?
Is there a crawlspace
or something like that?
When the ship goes into
lockdown. all vents are sealed.
Guys. I can't breathe. Guys...
( wheezing )
- What are you doing?
- Take off his helmet now.
Breathe.
Look. there's still some air
in here. okay?
Don't speak. Small breaths.
Use as little oxygen
as you can. okay?
Emergency situation.
Emergency situation in R Deck.
aft section above
maintenance holding.
We have workers suffocating
behind a sealed doorway.
- Send help!
- Can we override lockdown
and get that door open
from here?
Not without access to
the life support systems. no.
They'd have to do it manually.
Where the hell have you been?
Sorry. I can't... it...
- Malfunction... and...
- Our diagnostics have crashed.
and we can find where the
problem is with life support.
We need you to fix this.
- You hear me now?
- Yes. thank you. Much better.
Can you fix it?
Software malfunction?
Ah. it's below my paygrade.
Get a worker to do it.
- Fix it.
- All right. um.
I'd need assistance
from my team.
- I'd need time...
- Yeah. well. we don't have any bleeding time.
There is no air
left in this ship.
so when the helmets run out.
we're all dead.
Fix this.
Trent! Thank God.
Well. you brilliant boy.
You found an oxygen tank
from surgical?
Why didn't I think of that?
But how did you get out
of the infirmary?
I rewired the lock.
One of just a few benefits
of a misplaced youth.
Hurry. We have to get to R Deck.
- I can't fix it.
- What the hell do you mean you can't fix it?
- You installed it.
- Sorry. I can't.
- Why can't you fix it?
- Because I'm not Jasper Dades.
- What?
- My names Malcolm Perry.
I'm a transpo scrub.
I don't know
the first thing about this.
- Where is the real guy?
- I don't know.
I took his place on the ship.
- I impersonated him.
- Stop!
I should kill you right now.
Arrest this piece of shit.
Come on.
Ensign Stein. go through
every crew member.
Find anyone who has
advanced coding education
or life support systems training
and bring them here.
Lane. Lane. you guys
find anything yet?
Nothing. but we still have
a few more stations to check.
Is this all my fault?
Because I rerouted the power?
God help us.
( shallow breathing )
Engineering! Engineering!
- We need help!
- Hey. Hey.
Hey. uh.
I just wanted to tell you
that I appreciate everything
you ever did for me.
Don't talk.
There are people coming.
- And I need you...
- Shh.
- I need you know that...
- You're wasting oxygen.
- I love you.
Harris!
Step aside!
We have a locksmith onboard.
Who knew?
Hurry!
Come on. baby. Come on.
We need to get them
all to med bay. stat!
Here you go. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Lieutenant Garnet.
the three candidates are here.
I know this is not
your area of expertise.
but if any of you have any
knowledge of these systems.
how to crack it open. debug it...
I haven't studied
life support systems since
my junior year at community...
Garnet: We don't expect you
to be experts.
It's stuck in a Barstow loop.
- What?
- Named after Elliot Barstow.
who created
the original coding language.
It's kind of a known flaw.
Usually happens in power
failures or extreme surges.
- But can you break it?
- I think I can.
- Then do it. Come on.
- Um. okay. uh...
It's deceptively easy.
which is why so many people
have a hard time
with this software.
Everyone expects
normal security protocols.
but Barstow is essentially lazy
and only wants to work
on the parts that interested
him. so bypassed norms.
It's probably why his stuff
is so much less expensive.
Uh. um...
- ( chimes )
- Done.
No. now we need it to tell us
why we're losing oxygen.
- Yeah. of course. Sorry. I got all caught up.
- Okay. come on!
- ( gasps )
- ( sighing )
Automated voice:
Malfunction identified.
Lane. prepare a team
for an emergency EVA.
I am way ahead of you.
I'll be out in five.
I'm sending the diagnostics
findings to you now.
We've identified the source
of the problem.
Correction. Alicia Nevins did.
( grunting )
We found it.
Sealing the breach now.
Attention crew.
the oxygen crisis is over.
We're back online
and lockdown has been released.
You may remove your helmets.
( beeping )
( beeping intensifies )
Give me 20 cc's andestrine.
20 cc's andestrine.
( beeping continues )
He's not reacting.
Give him 15 cc's palastrimol.
15 cc's palastrimol.
We're losing him. doc.
Nothing. 20 cc's of cantastro.
- Come on. come on!
- 20 cc's cantastro.
( flatlining )
I'm so sorry.
You saved a lot of people
today. Trent.
You're a hero.
Nice job. Truly.
Elliot Barstow?
I did a thesis on him for extra credit
when I went for my coding master's.
But that was before I decided to do
a master's in atmospheric science.
Wait. you've got two bleeding
master's degrees? How old are you?
Next month I turn 19.
And four degrees actually.
Right. And you work
where on the ship?
- Waste management.
- Yeah. well. not anymore.
Alicia Nevins. you are
now chief life support.
Congratulations.
Welcome to the bridge.
You fixed the oxygen? See?
- You didn't need my help...
- Why'd you do it?
You're kidding me. right?
Everyone wanted
to be on this ship.
the first ark sent to the planet
with the highest
probability of success.
- I mean. come on.
- How?
I paid a hacker
to make Jasper think
he was reassigned to Ark 2.
Forged ID files so I
could show up in his place.
- But your DNA is...
- Is matched against the master DNA catalogs.
You think they can't
be hacked. too?
They told us Earth had 70 years.
That's why they started
the Ark program.
What if it's only ten? Five?
In a couple days. the representative
council will meet to decide your fate.
and I'm recommending
the death penalty.
You know I'm not the only one.
Lots of people faked
their way onto this ship.
It's not just me who ain't
who they say they are.
Six people died.
We almost lost
the entire ship because of you.
Wait. Okay. wait. Wait. wait.
Wait. Think about it
before you make that
recommendation to the council.
Now. I know a lot
of other people
who have committed crimes
who are on this ship.
What stage of death
is bargaining?
I've been to a lot of places
and I've seen things.
( scoffs )
Like a bar
in Jacksonville. Florida.
You know. the kind where cadets
hang out at and drink a bit too much.
Met a lot of people there.
including a sexy cadet
with hair-trigger anger issues.
I believe her name was Denise?
Yeah. yeah.
I'm pretty sure it was Denise.
A shame what happened. Tragic.
But maybe I'm mistaken.
We'll have to see
how good my memory is.
You heard the evidence. Several of you
in this room have heard his confession.
Operational protocol calls for
punishment to be anywhere
between a three month
imprisonment and execution.
Would anyone like to give
their recommendation?
We should hear from the accused
before we pass judgment.
He should have the right
to speak on his own behalf.
Have him brought
to this chamber.
Lane:
This season on "The Ark"...
Lane: And how we supposed
to investigate what hit us?
Some kind of crystal thing
wedged in there.
- Aye. they look like diamonds.
- Could've been a weapon.
We're the only people in history
to go this far in space.
I wish you would've taken the
cryo pod next to mine like I asked.
Do we even know who she is?
She didn't train with the rest of us.
Eva: I never understood
why that rule even existed.
that couples couldn't be
in the same Ark.
- Something to do with genetic diversity.
- What?
We need Garnet out
of the picture permanently.
I never thought I'd hear such
drastic measures coming from you.
Kabir:
I've seen your medical records.
They're too perfect to be real.
I just thought if I talked about
it first. I might chicken out.
so I just kind of like...
Lieutenant Lane.
Keep an eye on that one.
Angus: What the heck kind
of knife is this?
I think I know
who the murderer is.
How does Lane make a call
from the sector of a ship
that doesn't exist?
- ( alarm blaring )
- Shit.
Our drift has taken us
right into a collision course
with an asteroid.
Detaching in three. two...
- Wake up. dummy.
- You love me.
Aah! Ow!
Initiate faster
than light travel.
- What's happening to us?
- Proximity alert.
There's a ship approaching.
- From where?
- I don't know.
( music playing )